Q-learning is an Off-policy variant of TD learning.
Q 学习是一种 TD 学习的离线策略变体
Let's see how we can adapt it to work with function approximation.
我们看看如何调整它 以便用于函数逼近
Just like SARSA, we initialize parameters w arbitrarily,
和 SARSA 一样 我们随机地初始化参数
and define an epsilon greedy policy pi based on the Q-values.
并根据 Q 值定义一个 Epsilon 贪婪策略 π
Over multiple episodes, we use this epsilon greedy policy
在多个阶段中 我们使用该 Epsilon 贪婪策略
to repeatedly take an action and observe the reward and next state.
不断采取动作并观察奖励和下个状态
The main difference is in the update step.
主要区别在于更新步骤
Instead of picking the next action from the same epsilon greedy policy,
我们不再根据相同的 Epsilon 贪婪策略选择下个动作
we choose an action greedily,
而是贪婪地选择一个动作
which would maximize the expected value going forward.
该动作将最大化后续预期值
Note that we do not actually take this action,
注意 我们并非实际地采取该动作
it is only used for performing the update.
而是用于执行更新步骤
In fact, we don't even need to pick this action,
实际上 我们甚至不需要选择该动作
we can simply use the max Q value for the next state.
我们可以在下个状态使用最大 Q 值
This is why Q-learning is considered an off-policy method.
因此 Q 学习被视为离线策略方法
We use one policy to take actions,
我们根据一个策略采取动作
the epsilon greedy policy pi,
即 Epsilon 贪婪策略 π
and yet another policy to perform value updates, a greedy policy.
并根据另一个策略更新值 即贪婪策略
Although both of them are defined on the same underlying Q-values,
虽然这两个策略都根据相同的底层 Q 值进行定义
these two are indeed different policies.
但这两个策略实际上是不同的策略
Alright, this is what the Q-learning algorithm looks like for episodic tasks.
对于阶段性任务 Q 学习算法看起来就是这样
We can use the same algorithm for continuing tasks by treating
我们也可以将同一算法用于连续性任务
the whole unending sequence as one long episode
将整个无止境的序列当做一个很长的阶段
or modify it slightly to remove the concept of episodes.
或者稍加修改 取消阶段这一概念
Both forms are equivalent,
这两种形式是等效的
in either case we may need some additional criteria to figure out when
在这两种情况下 我们可能需要额外的条件
we have fully learned the task or to detect if we're failing miserably.
来判断我们是否完全学会了任务或完全出错了
Let's take a moment to compare SARSA and Q learning.
我们来比较下 SARSA 和 Q 学习
SARSA is an On-policy algorithm that follows the same policy that it is learning.
SARSA 是一个异同策略算法 遵守的是要学习的同一策略
In general, this is more suitable for online learning.
通常更适合在线学习
At any point of time,
在任何时间点
you are using the most updated policy as per your interactions with the environment.
你都使用通过与环境互动获得的最新策略
However, it also means that if you use Epsilon Greedy action selection,
但是 如果你使用 Epsilon 贪婪动作选择法
which is necessary to encourage exploration,
以便促进探索效果
then this randomness also affects the Q-values that are learned.
那么这种随机性还会影响到学习的 Q 值
On the other hand, Q learning is an Off-policy method.
另一方面 Q 学习是一种新策略方法
Meaning the policy it follows to choose
即选择动作时遵守的策略
actions is different from the policy it is learning.
与要学习的策略不同
This can lead to bad online performance,
这样可能会导致糟糕的在线效果
because there is a disconnect between
因为你要学习的策略
the policy you are learning and the one you are following.
与遵守的策略之间不相关
But the good thing is that the Epsilon Greedy nature of
不过比较好的一点是动作选择的 Epsilon 贪婪特性
action selection does not impact the Q-values learned.
不会影响到学习的 Q 值
Thus the two approaches have their pros and cons,
因此这两种方法各有利弊
and which algorithm you choose will depend on the characteristics of the environment
要选择哪个方法 取决于环境特性
and your preferences regarding online performance versus more accurate learning.
以及你是更关心在线性能还是学习准确性
The biggest reason Off-policy methods like Q-learning have got
Q 学习等新策略方法
so much attention is that they decouple
之所以变得如此热门
the actions and agent takes in the environment from its learning process.
是因为它们使智能体在环境中采取的动作与学习流程不再相关
That gives us the opportunity to build different variations of our learning algorithm.
这样我们便有机会构建学习算法的不同变体
For instance, you can use a more exploratory policy
例如 你可以在采取动作时遵守更加探索性的策略
while acting and yet learned the optimal value function.
并学习最优值函数
Yes, the online performance will be bad,
没错 在线性能会很糟糕
but at some point we can stop exploring and follow the optimal policy for better results.
但是在某个时间点 我们可以停止探索并遵守最优策略 以获得更好的结果
In fact, the policy used to take actions need not be the agent zone,
实际上 采取动作时遵守的策略不一定必须只限于智能体
a human can demonstrate what actions to take,
人类可以演示所采取的动作
and the agent can learn from observing the effects of those actions.
智能体可以通过观察这些动作的效果学习规律
It also makes it easier to learn offline or in batches
并且离线学习或批量学习过程更加轻松
since an update to the policy need not be performed at every step.
因为不需要在每个时间步更新策略
This as we will see is critical for
这对可靠地训练强化学习神经网络来说非常关键
reliably training neural networks for reinforcement learning
很快我们就会感受到这一点